<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Episodes on Generative Artistry</title>
    <link>https://generativeartistry.com/episodes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Episodes on Generative Artistry</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 09:59:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://generativeartistry.com/episodes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Math.random(3) - Chess</title>
      <link>https://generativeartistry.com/episodes/random-chess/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 09:59:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://generativeartistry.com/episodes/random-chess/</guid>
      <description>Chess! Tim and Ruth explore the idea of learning something new, and the difficulties you have when you have to start from scratch. Looking at the steps you have to go through to become good at something, including figuring out where you&amp;rsquo;re bad at it, and finding out where to improve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matt DesLauriers</title>
      <link>https://generativeartistry.com/episodes/matt-deslauriers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 09:59:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://generativeartistry.com/episodes/matt-deslauriers/</guid>
      <description>Matt DesLauriers Ruth and Tim speak to artist &amp;amp; creative coder Matt Delauries about his process, goals when creating, and all things generative art.!
For those that don&amp;rsquo;t know Matt, his open-source code around generative art is a great place to start, as well as his many many conference talks and workshops, and of course all the beautiful beautiful art.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sharell Bryant</title>
      <link>https://generativeartistry.com/episodes/sharell-bryant/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 09:59:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://generativeartistry.com/episodes/sharell-bryant/</guid>
      <description>Sharell Bryant! Ruth and Tim sit down with the very talented Sharell Bryant! We talk about Sharell&amp;rsquo;s stunning audio explorations on the web. As well as keeping motivated and on track with side projects, different ways to learn and grow, which tools you can utilize to help along the way!
For those that don&amp;rsquo;t know her, Sharell Bryant is a programmer and singer-songwriter in NYC interested in exploring the intersection of art, technology, and education.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Algorithms</title>
      <link>https://generativeartistry.com/episodes/algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 09:59:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://generativeartistry.com/episodes/algorithms/</guid>
      <description>Algorithms Aside from being the word that everyone says when they don&amp;rsquo;t want to explain what the code is doing, algorithms are one of the backbones of generative art. Join us, as we dissect some of the most common algorithms in generative art.
Full transcription incoming!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Math.random(2) - Creativity</title>
      <link>https://generativeartistry.com/episodes/creativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 09:59:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://generativeartistry.com/episodes/creativity/</guid>
      <description>Creativity Another random chat where Ruth and Tim find themselves deeply off our intended topic, but keep exploring and surfacing ideas and thoughts we have about Creativity.
Full transcription incoming!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jake Albaugh</title>
      <link>https://generativeartistry.com/episodes/jake-albaugh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 09:59:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://generativeartistry.com/episodes/jake-albaugh/</guid>
      <description>Jake Albaugh! Jake&amp;rsquo;s projects expand across a broad range of topics with the web in common. Its a blast talking to him, and going over some of the weird and wonderful creations he&amp;rsquo;s made.
Full transcription incoming!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tooling</title>
      <link>https://generativeartistry.com/episodes/tooling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 09:59:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://generativeartistry.com/episodes/tooling/</guid>
      <description>Lets talk about random Tim and Ruth have a blast talking about the different tools and techniques in generative art, including some of the history behind them.
Full transcription incoming!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Math.random(1)</title>
      <link>https://generativeartistry.com/episodes/random/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 09:59:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://generativeartistry.com/episodes/random/</guid>
      <description>Lets talk about random Random numbers are everywhere in generative art, and everywhere in coding. There&amp;rsquo;s so many ways to approach this topic, so buckle up and have a listen to our take.
Full transcription incoming!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charlie Gleason</title>
      <link>https://generativeartistry.com/episodes/charlie-gleason/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 09:59:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://generativeartistry.com/episodes/charlie-gleason/</guid>
      <description>Amazing guest, Charlie Gleason! Our first guest! The talented Charlie Gleason joins us and chats about his journey into creative coding and the things he has built. All the way through Actionscript, sound engineering, design and of course there&amp;rsquo;s some generative art in there!
Be sure to check out Charlie&amp;rsquo;s Website, and follow him on Twitter
&amp;ndash;
Ruth: Charlie How are you?
Charlie: I&amp;rsquo;m very well, how are you?
And I got some friends and I&amp;rsquo;m sorry if they are listening because they did their best, but the end product like was not something that was gonna work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generative Art and Creative Code</title>
      <link>https://generativeartistry.com/episodes/generative-art-and-creative-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 09:59:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://generativeartistry.com/episodes/generative-art-and-creative-code/</guid>
      <description>Generative art, creative code, and the world around us! Tim and Ruth jump right into creative code and generative art, this episode we talk about the what, when and why&amp;rsquo;s.
&amp;ndash;
Tim: In a non-nonphysical form. I&amp;rsquo;ve got some history stuff here. New tendencies exhibitions. So this is the first exhibitions that, this was the first series of exhibitions that brought computers or coding specifically into the art forms that they were displaying.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Generative Art Podcast</title>
      <link>https://generativeartistry.com/episodes/introducing-the-generative-art-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 09:59:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://generativeartistry.com/episodes/introducing-the-generative-art-podcast/</guid>
      <description>Introducing our Generative Art Podcast! In this episode Ruth and Tim get to talking about what they want to get out of this podcast, where we want to take it, and preaching the good word of creative code, and generative art.
&amp;ndash;
Ruth: Oh yeah.
Tim: Exactly and yourself.
Tim: Glass, led lighting, playdough.
Ruth: Cool. Thanks Tim.
Tim: Thanks Ruth. </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
